Abhishek Bagchi

Asansol, West Bengal, India



abhishek.bagchi1994@gmail.com



9547513665



linkedin.com/in/abhishek-bagchi

Summary

Rational, critical-thinking IT Analyst with 6 years of experience enhancing operations for organizations through information systems solutions. Proven track record of transforming specific business goals related to growth and efficiency improvements into new system designs. Working as a Asp.Net Developer for the past 5 years now.

Experience



Senior Associate

PwC

Nov 2021 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Working as Microservices Developer

- Worked on creating Azure Timer trigger Functions
- Worked on microservices API, Fluent Validation
- Worked in U-SQL scripts for ADLA

Worked on MVC developer

- Created new validation in cshtml files with javascript
- Worked with Entity Framework for Data fetching



IT Analyst

Tata Consultancy Services

Apr 2020 - Oct 2021 (1 year 7 months)

Worked in Co-Op (UK Client) as a Dotnet (C#) Developer

Project Smart-Cash: Implemented integration of CCI device inside Stores Till with exciting Cash Solution so that Store Users can work seamlessly without worrying in of Cash Theft. (Asp Dot net with SQL Server)

Project Central Smart-Cash Application: Implemented a Central Application so that All the stores Smart-Cash Related data can be shown to Corporate Users (NetCore, SQL Server, React)

Project In-Control: Implemented windows scheduler task to fetch the data from registry and Update it in the Database with Batch script.



System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Sep 2018 - Apr 2020 (1 year 8 months)

Worked as Dot Net Developer in Lidl (German Client)

Project Kaufland: Implemented reusable components to be used in different parts of the application

Worked in Refactoring the code with StyleCop and Resharper

Worked in TDD approach with nUnit and JustMock

Worked as Dot Net Developer in Co-Op (UK Client)

Project RBT-InControl: Implemented retail business transform logic for In-Control Application so that

SAP can fetch the desired data from Backend

Project SmartCash: Implemented CCI Integration in Co-Op store till

Assistant System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Sep 2017 - Sep 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Worked in Waitrose (UK Client) as Support executive

Project Customer Experience: worked in waitrose.com transformation from legacy WCS to AWS.

Worked in DB2, Shell Script, Site Confidence, App Dynamics

Worked in AWS in CloudWatch and in Kibana.

Worked in apps like App Dynamics and Site Confidance.

Assistant System Engineer Trainee

Tata Consultancy Services

Sep 2016 - Sep 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Trained in C++, Unix, Oracle in TCS Initial Learning Program.

Worked in Home Depot (USA Client) as Unix Shell Script Developer

Created Shell Scripts to fetch data from server with conditional formatting.

Education



West Bengal Board of Secondary Education

Middle School Diploma, Middle School Diploma 2005 - 2010

Passed with 670 Marks out of 800 (83.75%)

West Bengal Council of Higher Secondary Education

High School Diploma, High School Diploma

2010 - 2012

Passed with 391 Marks out of 500 (78.2%.)

Birbhum institute of Engineering and Technology

Engineer's Degree, Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering 2012 - 2016

Passed with over all 8.39 DGPA, As top 10% of the class

Licenses & Certifications



Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate - Microsoft

Skills

ASP.NET • JavaScript • SQL • Unit Testing • HTML5 • C# • Windows Batch Scripting • ECMAScript • .NET Core • ASP.NET MVC

Honors & Awards

Above and Beyond Award - PwC India

Mar 2022

Appreciator's note: Thank you for your wonderful contribution in improving the quality standeards of the project an mentoring other team membersin your own expertise areas. Well done!!

On the Spot Award - Tata Consultancy Services

Dec 2017

Appreciator's note: Good Work Abhishek.

Thank you very much for all your hard work and support during the seasonal setup, execution and take down activities. Your application ownership and support helped us to achieve a clean 100% defect free seasonal setup 2017.

On the Spot Award - Tata Consultancy Services

Feb 2020

Appreciator's note: Congratulations!! You are finally graduated!! Appreciate the effort put by you for XccelerateNinja Full Stack Developer Program

Best Team Award - Tata Consultancy Services

Jan 2018

Appreciator's note :Alone we can do so little and together we can do so much' this team has proved that this is possible by exhibiting their rigor during the Peak

Star of the Month - Tata Consultancy Services

Aug 2019

Appreciator's note: Abhishek is one of the most valued member of InControl Development team. He has made a great contribution in one of the flagship project of COOP (Cash Management CCi integration). He has taken up the complete ownership of multiple complex modules and delivered the end to end solution. Within the short span of time he has understood the business's need and converted them into the system level design. We are proud to have a committed team member like him. Wish you good luck for the upcoming days.